MATIAS ARIEL REBOLLEDO ARAVENA

Santiago | CL | +56956627476 | LinkedIn | GitHub | maravenarwork@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

Junior Fullstack Developer with focus on Spring Boot JAVA and React.JS stack. Experience of 2 years working as a Language Coach and 1 year as a Language Quality Assurance (LQA). Core soft skills such as adaptability, effective communication, teamwork, persistence, growth mindset, work ethic, among others; and hard skills such as MS Office and webinar platforms (Zoom, Teams, Discord, etc.), PC hardware and maintenance.

EDUCATION

GENERATION CHILE Online, CL

Full Stack Junior JAVA Developer. Training on fundamental competencies:

2022

- Front-End: HTML, CSS, JS, React.JS, Bootstrap, NPM, JQuery, among others
- Back-End: JAVA, MySQL, SQL, JUnit and JPA, Springboot, API Rest, among others
- Complementary: Git, GitHub, Agile SCRUM (Trello, JIRA), VSCode IDEs, Laragon, DBeaver, among others

PLATZI ACADEMY Online, CL

EFL/ESP specialist

2021 - 2022

• Advanced C1 English training Certification

PROJECT AND WORK EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE LANGUAGES SPECIALIST

Online, IE, GB, DK, CL

EFL/ESP Coach and Professor

2020 - 2022

- Planning and implementation of classes and English language coaching sessions (EFL/ESP) focused on Spanish speakers.
- Study and research of different and specific areas in order to plan and implement ESP classes.
- Design, improvement, translation and implementation of audio-visual material for EFL/ESP classes.
- Continuous participation in multicultural conventions and social meetings related to EFL/ESP.
- Support in EFL curricular tasks related to a professor in charge of high school education in Santiago, CL.

KEYWORDS STUDIOS Dublin, IE

LatAm and European Spanish LQA/FQA tester

2019 - 2020

- Proofreading texts and video game content (spelling, syntax, typography and localisation) in contrast to English sources.
- Checking texts for consistency and recommending changes when necessary, according to regional idioms and targets.
- Continuous bug and issues logging on digital platforms (JIRA, TestRail, Bonsai and MemoQ basics).
- Implementation of both ENG SPA and SPA ENG translations according to clients' needs, ensuring both their quality and accuracy, as well as per the sources provided by them.
- Ensuring subtitles audio and VO sync in both timing and language syntax.
- Providing constant support and back up to different colleagues regarding to both language and tech issues.

COMPLEMENTARY, LANGUAGES, AND INTERESTS

SCRUM STUDY Online, CL

SCRUM Agile Fundamentals

Jun. 2022

 Participation in Agile SCRUM fundamentals workshop, training on team, projects' flow, planning, implementation and review of SCRUM methodology concepts.

LANGUAGES:

• Spanish (Native), English (Advanced C1).

INTERESTS:

• Learning about new technologies (IT), Languages practise, Travelling and Hiking, Reading, Playing the guitar, bass and fiddle, Rollerblading, Archery, etc.